Guide to the Joseph Bruchac Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- July 2006 Acquisition, 1961-2006; 29.63 linear feet (31 boxes)
  - Writings
    - Writings of Others
      - Hite, Sid. Stick and Whittle, 1999 (Box 134)
      - Krapf, Norbert, undated (Box 134)
      - Kudaka. "Exiles & Passages of Return" and "Involuntary Birth" (partial manuscript), 1977-1978 (Box 134)
      - McKnight, Osborn. I am of Irelaunde, 2000 (Box 134)
      - Nduka, Uche, 1998 (Box 134)
      - Nkurumeh, Barthosa (Nigerian poet), 2001 (Box 134)
      - Ogden, Hugh, undated (Box 134)
      - Okai, Atukewei, undated (Box 134)
      - Opyr, Linda Elena, undated (Box 134)
      - Osborne-McKnight, Juilene
        See: McKnight, Osborn
      - Rose, Al. "The Autobiography of a Kiss", 1995 (Box 134)
      - Schoemaker, Lynne, 1998 (Box 134)
      - Shipley, Vivian, undated (Box 134)
      - Shore, Diane ZuHone. Comments for Harper Collins on This Is the Feast, undated (Box 134)
      - Swain, Gwenyth. Little Crow, 2003 (Box 134)
      - Turner, Peter. "A Mind with Wings", undated (Box 135)
      - Van Leeuwen, 2003; 2 (Box 135)
      - Wallace, George, 1999 (Box 135)
      - Weiner, Alan, "Lost Woman", 1994 (Box 135)
      - Yep, Laurence. The Journal of Wong Ming-Chung, 1999 (Box 135)
      - Yolen, Jane. Roanoke, 2000 (Box 135)
      - Yolen, Jane. Harcourt, undated; 2 (Box 135)
  - Bookings
    - Bookings, 1997-1998; 21 (Box 136)
    - Bookings, itineraries, and queries, 1997-1999; 21 (Box 137)
    - Bookings and thank you letters, 1999; 21 (Box 138)
    - Bookings, 2000-2001; 10 (Box 139)
    - Bookings, 2000-2002; 23 (Box 140)
    - Bookings, 2002-2003; 23 (Box 141)
    - Bookings, 2002-2003; 26 (Box 142)
    - Bookings, 2003-2005; 28 (Box 143)
    - Bookings, 2004-2005; 27 (Box 144)
    - Bookings, undated; 1 CD (Box 144)
    - AVI, Weekend All Things Considered (audiocassette), 1998 July 12; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002091243023)
      Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile.
  - Computer media
    - [no label information], 2006-ycal-47-0001; 1 (Box 145)
    - POCAHONTAS Microsoft Word 4.0 MAC, 2006-ycal-47-0002; 1 (Box 145)
    - CRAZY HORSE, 2006-ycal-47-0003; 1 (Box 145)
    - [no label information], 2006-ycal-47-0004; 1 (Box 145)
    - LAND INA CARN [inscribed], 2006-ycal-47-0005; 1 (Box 145)
    - [no label information], 2006-ycal-47-0006; 1 (Box 145)
    - [no label information], 2006-ycal-47-0007; 1 (Box 145)
    - JOSEPH BRUCHAC 2/99 CURRICULUM FAIR, 2006-ycal-47-0008; 1 (Box 145)
    - Joseph Bruchac Curriculum Fair 2/1999, 2006-ycal-47-0009; 1 (Box 145)
    - Squanto's Story by Joe Bruchac Word 4.0 MAC, 2006-ycal-47-0010; 1 (Box 145)
    - Squanto 99, 2006-ycal-47-0011; 1 (Box 145)
    - HARCOURT BRACE, 2006-ycal-47-0012; 1 (Box 176)
    - BRIDGEWATER, 2006-ycal-47-0013; 1 (Box 176)
    - BRIDGEWATER 94-95, 2006-ycal-47-0014; 1 (Box 176)
    - BRIDGEWATER 11/96, 2006-ycal-47-0015; 1 (Box 176)
    - BRIDGEWATER 1996-, 2006-ycal-47-0016; 1 (Box 176)
    - CANDLEWICK 1998, 2006-ycal-47-0017; 1 (Box 176)
    - CANDLEWICK, 2006-ycal-47-0018; 1 (Box 176)
    - DEFENDERS OF WILDLIFE, 2006-ycal-47-0019; 1 (Box 176)
    - FULCRUM 99, 2006-ycal-47-0020; 1 (Box 176)
    - FULCRUM 92-95, 2006-ycal-47-0021; 1 (Box 176)
    - MOHEGAN NATION 1996, 2006-ycal-47-0022; 1 (Box 176)
    - NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC 1991, 2006-ycal-47-0023; 1 (Box 176)
    - NEW PRESS storytelling essay, 2006-ycal-47-0024; 1 (Box 176)
    - PRENTICE HALL POETRY '96 HOLT S+S MACMILLAN, 2006-ycal-47-0025; 1 (Box 176)
    - RANDOM HOUSE 98, 2006-ycal-47-0026; 1 (Box 176)
    - SCHOLASTIC NET 1997, 2006-ycal-47-0027; 1 (Box 176)
    - WALKER 97-98, 2006-ycal-47-0028; 1 (Box 176)
    - WITH VISIBLE BREATH, 2006-ycal-47-0029; 1 (Box 176)
    - Joseph Bruchac, Poems Microsoft Word 4.0 Mac, 2006-ycal-47-0030; 1 (Box 176)
    - Essays #1 up to 6/94, 2006-ycal-47-0031; 1 (Box 176)
    - Glossary & Pronunciation key WORDS + NAMES KOL, KOA, 2006-ycal-47-0032; 1 (Box 176)
    - THE CREATOR'S GAME by Joseph Bruchac 7/96 MAC. WORD 4.0, 2006-ycal-47-0033; 1 (Box 176)
    - JOE'S FOLDER 97 discards, 2006-ycal-47-0034; 1 (Box 176)
    - HARPER 94 back-up, 2006-ycal-47-0035; 1 (Box 176)
    - REVIEWS, 2006-ycal-47-0036; 1 (Box 176)
    - TRANSFERS, 2006-ycal-47-0037; 1 (Box 176)
    - Joe's folder 98 SCHOLASTIC 98, 2006-ycal-47-0038; 1 (Box 176)
    - Jim NATIONAL GEO, 2006-ycal-47-0039; 1 (Box 176)
    - GRP 1998, 2006-ycal-47-0040; 1 (Box 176)
    - HARCOURT 98 Squanto's Story, 2006-ycal-47-0041; 1 (Box 176)
    - MICROSOFT WORD, 2006-ycal-47-0042; 1 (Box 176)
    - HOLY COW PAESS TURTLE MEAT short story, 2006-ycal-47-0043; 1 (Box 176)
    - [no label information], 2006-ycal-47-0044; 1 (Box 176)
    - NAD 1993 Holt 1995 N.A.D. 1993 Holt 1995, 2006-ycal-47-0045; 1 (Box 176)
    - NATIVE AUTHORS CATALOG 6/96, 2006-ycal-47-0046; 1 (Box 176)
    - BREAKFAST SERIALS, 2006-ycal-47-0047; 1 (Box 176)
    - Breaks Foxy, 2006-ycal-47-0048; 1 (Box 176)
    - Candlewick, 2006-ycal-47-0049; 1 (Box 176)
    - Darby Creek, 2006-ycal-47-0050; 1 (Box 176)
    - Dial Codetalker, 2006-ycal-47-0051; 1 (Box 176)
    - Dial Plays NATIVE AMERICAN PLAYS DIAL 1996, 2006-ycal-47-0052; 1 (Box 176)
    - Dial Wabi, 2006-ycal-47-0053; 1 (Box 176)
    - Dial The Winter People, 2006-ycal-47-0054; 1 (Box 176)
    - Fulcrum, 2006-ycal-47-0055; 1 (Box 176)
    - Harcourt, 2006-ycal-47-0056; 1 (Box 176)
    - Harper Skeleton Man 2001, 2006-ycal-47-0057; 1 (Box 176)
    - Harper The Dark Pond, 2006-ycal-47-0058; 1 (Box 176)
    - Harper Return of Skeleton Man, 2006-ycal-47-0059; 1 (Box 176)
    - Harper Bear Walker, 2006-ycal-47-0060; 1 (Box 176)
    - Harper Whisper in The Dark, 2006-ycal-47-0061; 1 (Box 176)
    - Holy Cow Foot of the Mountain Word 4.0, 2006-ycal-47-0062; 1 (Box 176)
    - JB A-L, 2006-ycal-47-0063; 1 (Box 176)
    - JB M-Z, 2006-ycal-47-0064; 1 (Box 176)
    - LEE + LOW, 2006-ycal-47-0065; 1 (Box 176)
    - Milkweed At the End of Ridge Road, 2006-ycal-47-0066; 1 (Box 176)
    - National Geographic 1, 2006-ycal-47-0067; 1 (Box 176)
    - National Geographic 2, 2006-ycal-47-0068; 1 (Box 176)
    - Novels 1, 2006-ycal-47-0069; 1 (Box 176)
    - Novels 2, 2006-ycal-47-0070; 1 (Box 176)
    - Parabola, 2006-ycal-47-0071; 1 (Box 176)
    - Parker, 2006-ycal-47-0072; 1 (Box 176)
    - PLAYS, 2006-ycal-47-0073; 1 (Box 176)
    - Poetry, 2006-ycal-47-0074; 1 (Box 176)
    - Scholastic Journal of Jesse Smoke, 2006-ycal-47-0075; 1 (Box 176)
    - Scholastic GERONIMO, 2006-ycal-47-0076; 1 (Box 176)
    - Scholastic Hidden Roots, 2006-ycal-47-0077; 1 (Box 176)
    - Stories, 2006-ycal-47-0078; 1 (Box 176)
    - Stories 2, 2006-ycal-47-0079; 1 (Box 176)
    - Walker, 2006-ycal-47-0080; 1 (Box 176)
- September 2006 Acquisition, undated; 0.21; (1 box)
  Contains materials removed from books owned by Bruchac, which have been cataloged separately.
  Unarranged.
  - Manuscript materials removed from books, undated; 4 (Box 146)
- Other Acquisitions, undated; 0.21; (1 box)
  - Manuscript materials removed from books, undated (Box 147)